This way.
こちらへ。
Are you kidding me?
I can't believe this is happening...
《マジってか…
あるんだな こんなこと》
Oops.
おっと！ 大丈夫か？
You okay?
Yeah!
あぁ サンキューってば… え？
Thanks, man.
Huh?
あ… あっ！
ああ～っ！
You jerk!
このやろ～！
Divine retribution for you.
ヘヘヘッ バチが当たった。
ぶっ殺す！
I'll kill that guy!
Okay, that won't do.
(ヤマト)はい ダメですよ。
Damn him, damn him,
damn him, damn him!
クソソラが クソソラが… クソ！
ニヒヒッ！
ソラ なんてことを！
Sora! What have you done?!
Okay, okay, my bad.
(ソラ)はいはい ボクが悪いです！
I'll kill him...
I'm definitely going to kill him.
殺す ぜってぇ殺す！
No, no, you'll receive
divine punishment if you do.
いやいや ホントにバチが当たるよ。
Welcome back, Chiriku-sama.
(忍僧たち)
おかえりなさいませ 地陸様。
How are things progressing?
(地陸)首尾は？
(忍僧)はっ！
Sir! We have already sent Shinobi monks
to the remaining three hidden tombs
(忍僧)すでに 他の３つの隠し墓➡
ナウマ様 トウウ様 セイト様の墓所に
忍僧たちを向かわせております。
of Nauma-sama, Tou'u-sama
and Seito-sama.
They are all the finest of
Fire Temple monks
いずれも火ノ寺きっての手練れ。
and arrangements have been made
for them to inform us immediately
異変があれば
直ちに知らせが入る手筈に…。
if something unusual happens.
キタネ様 ご遺骸の捜索には
数名をさいて当たっております。
We have assigned several men to
the search for the remains of Kitane-sama.
We have also tightened
temple security and are ready
(忍僧)寺の警護も強化し
もしもの場合に備えております。
just in case something happens.
Then I suppose we can rest easy...
ならば まずは安心か。
It took you guys long enough.
(ソラ)遅ぇんだよ。
Sora...!
(地陸)ソラ！
フンッ。
He's sure got an attitude problem!
なに？ あの態度！
アイツ… ん？
That jerk!
(地陸)ただいま戻りました。
We have returned.
These are the people from the Hidden Leaf
こちらは 私の要請に応えて
来てくださった➡
who came here in compliance
with our request.
木ノ葉の里の方々です。
Hello. I'm Captain Yamato.
どうも 隊長のヤマトです。
And this is Sakura, Sai
and Naruto.
彼らは サクラ サイ ナルト。
From the Leaf?
That is indeed reassuring.
(高僧)木ノ葉の… それは心強い。
That's right. Just leave it to us!
おう 任せておけってばよ！
We are prepared to move out
whenever necessary.
いつでも動けるよう
準備は できています。
Either way, you won't have to until
we hear from the Shinobi monks.
いずれにせよ 忍僧たちからの
連絡を待ったうえで…。
Until then, please come this way.
それまでは こちらで。
Once I fly,
habataitara
I won't be coming back, I said.
modorena ito itte
And I set out.
mezashita no wa
For that blue, blue sky.
aoi aoi ano sora
I haven't learned "sadness" yet.
kanashimi wa mada oboerarezu
And I'm just starting to grasp "misery".
setsunasa wa ima tsukami hajimeta
Even this feeling I hold towards you.
anata e to idaku kono kanjou mo
Is now turning into "words".
ima kotoba ni wakatteku
Waking up from the dream of this unknown world.
michi naru sekai no yume kara mezamete
I spread these wings and fly.
kono hane wo hiroge tobi datsu
Once I fly,
habataitara
I won't be coming back, I said.
modorena ito itte
And I set out.
mezashita no wa
For that blue, blue sky.
aoi aoi ano sora
Knowing I'll find the answer,
tsuki nuketara
If I pierce through it.
mitsukaru to shitte
if I break free,
furikiru hodo
From that blue, blue sky.
aoi aoi ano sora
Loneliness
奪われた死体 何に使うのかな？
I wonder what they'll use...
the stolen bodies for.
そうだね。 遺体がもつ情報が
欲しかったのか あるいは…。
Well, maybe they wanted the information
the bodies held...
or perhaps...
Summoning Jutsu: Reanimation!
((大蛇丸 : 口寄せ 穢土転生！
１つ ２つ！
One! Two!
３人目は ダメだったようね。
It appears the third one didn't work out.
(まぁ いいわ))
Oh well...
大蛇丸のように 遺体そのものを
利用する目的なのかもしれない。
Their objective might be to use
the body itself as Orochimaru did.
まぁ
そんな高度な術を使える連中が➡
Well, I doubt you'd come across a group
そういるとは思えないけどね。
that can use a powerful Jutsu
like that every day.
へぇ～ んじゃ
その隠し墓に眠る４人の忍って➡
No kidding?
Then the four Ninja resting
in those hidden tombs
must've been really powerful.
よっぽど偉かったんだな… うっ！
な… 何？
Wh-What?
偉いヤツらでした。
そして 何より いいヤツらでした。
They were remarkable Shinobi.
And most of all, they were good people.
(地陸)火ノ寺を中心とする
東西南北に位置する場所に➡
The tombs of Nauma, Seito,
Tou'u and Kitane are located
to the east, west, south and north
with the Fire Temple as the central point.
ナウマ セイト トウウ そして
キタネの墓が置かれております。
彼らは いずれも
守護忍十二士のメンバーでありました。
They were all members of
the Guardian Shinobi Twelve.
守護忍十二士…？
The Guardian Shinobi Twelve?
I've heard of them.
聞いたことがあります。
(サイ)名前だけは。
I've just heard the name.
あれ？ 有名なの…？
Huh? Are they famous?
まぁ 知る人ぞ知るって感じかな。
なっ…!?
Well, to those in the know,
I guess they're well known.
守護忍十二士とは
火ノ国の大名を守るために➡
The Guardian Shinobi Twelve
was an organization
comprised of elite Shinobi
gathered from within the nation
国じゅうから 精鋭を集めて
できた組織でね。
to protect the Feudal Lord of
the Land of Fire, you see.
Huh? But it's Shinobi from our Leaf Village
who protect the Land of Fire, right?
火ノ国を守るのは
オレたち 木ノ葉の里の忍だろ？
火ノ国を守るのは木ノ葉の里だよ。
Yes, the Hidden Leaf Village does
protect the Land of Fire.
でも里は あくまでも
国を守るための機関であって➡
But to be exact, a village is
an institution to protect the land.
大名個人を守るためだけの
組織じゃない。
It's not an organization
just for protecting
an individual Feudal Lord.
じゃあさ…。
Then...
First, the Feudal Lord who is
the apex of the land,
国を守るには まず
その頂点である大名を守ること。
must be protected in order
to protect that land.
(地陸)守護忍十二士とは
そのような考えを前提に➡
The Guardian Shinobi Twelve
is an organization
assembled with such
a concept as its foundation.
集められた組織なのです。
あの頃は 私も若かった。
I was also young back then.
火ノ国のため
命を投げ出すことも いとわぬと➡
I joined the Guardian Shinobi Twelve,
willing to lay down my life
for the Land of Fire.
守護忍十二士に参加したのです。
じゃあ 地陸さんも…？
Then you were also...!
I used to be.
元… ですがね。
ちなみに アスマさんも
元 守護忍十二士なんだよ。
Incidentally, Asuma-san also
used to be a member
of the Twelve Guardian Shinobi Warriors.
(サクラ/ナルト)へぇ～！
- What?!
Asuma, huh?
アスマか… 彼は 元気ですか？
Is he doing okay?
元気だってばよ！
Yeah! He's good!
この前もさ
修業のアドバイス もらったんだぜ。
He gave me some training advice
the other day.
ほぅ… そうですか。
Oh... I see.
…ということは➡
So that means...
今回の事件は 地陸さんにとって
アスマ先生にとってもですが➡
This incident...
to you and to Asuma-sensei...
仲間の墓を荒らされた
ということなのですね？
It means your friends' graves
were violated, right?
あの４人は 火ノ国のため
若くして命を落としたのです。
Those four people lost their lives
at a young age
for the sake of the Land of Fire.
(地陸)守護人十二士の中に➡
Within the Guardian Shinobi Twelve
a faction attempting to stage
a coup emerged...
クーデターを起こそうとする
一派が現れ➡
and that ended up dividing the twelve.
それが 十二士を二分したのです。
クーデターとは 強引な手段に
訴えてでも➡
A coup is an attempt to change a land
自分たちの
理想とする考えに➡
into one's ideal notions even if it
means resorting to a forceful approach.
国を変えようとする
行為のことだよ。
知ってるよ そのくらい…。
Even I know that!
People who radicalized the notion
of wanting to protect the Land of Fire
火ノ国を守りたい…
その思いが先鋭化して➡
過激な考えを持つ者たちが➡
and who possessed extreme ideologies
守護忍十二士の中に
現れてしまった。
ended up emerging within
the Guardian Shinobi Twelve.
そうだよ！ つまりさ…。
That's right! In other words...!
They couldn't leave matters
of the Land of Fire
火ノ国を なまぬるい
木ノ葉の里などに➡
to the moderate Hidden Leaf Village.
任せちゃおけないって
ことでしょう。
自分たち中心に 軍事力を
強化した国をつくろう。
They wanted to create
a land of strengthened military force
with themselves at the center...
or something like that.
…ってところかな。
Yeah, or something like that.
That's unforgivable!
いや そういうところかな。
許せねえな！
(サクラ)ナルト！
うん？
Naruto!
うるさい！
Keep quiet!
Right... Their plan was to break up
the Leaf Village and turn that military force
(地陸)そう…
木ノ葉の里を解体し➡
その軍事力を
大名中心の機関とする。
into an institution with
the Feudal Lord at the center.
彼らのプランは 現実に
大名を動かすところまで➡
It proceeded so far as to influence
the Feudal Lord.
進められていました。
そして同時に➡
And at the same time,
他国への戦をも準備していた。
they were making preparations
to attack other lands.
What did you say?!
何ですって！
Without making do with peace forged
with a delicate balance
五大国間の微妙なバランスで
築いた平和を よしとせず➡
among the Five Great Nations,
they waved the banner of
a noble cause in which
火ノ国が世界を統一し➡
the Land of Fire would unite the world
and total peace would be attained.
完全なる平和を手にするのだと
大義を掲げて…。
そんな 勝手な…！
That's so selfish...
Yes... War is war,
うむ… どんなに立派な
御託を並べても 戦は戦。
no matter how splendid
the song and dance may be.
さすがに大名も 彼らの
いきすぎた考えに気づき➡
As expected,
the Feudal Lord became aware
of their radical thinking and...
そして…。
(地陸)クーデターを
起こした６人は死にました。
The six people who staged
the coup died.
However, Kitane, Nauma,
Tou'u and Seito... also fell victim.
しかし キタネ ナウマ トウウ セイトの
４人も犠牲になってしまった。
I can't believe something
like that happened.
そんなことがあったなんて…。
The four people of
the hidden tombs were
(サイ)隠し墓の４人は
地陸さんや アスマ先生の友達…。
friends of Chiriku-san and Asuma-sensei.
ナルトや サクラの友達…
例えば サスケ君が死んで➡
For example, let's say...
our friend Sasuke were to die
and his body were to be stolen...
その死体が盗まれたとしたら…。
That's right.
そうだよね。
We can't forgive the people
who stole Kitane's body.
キタネさんのご遺体を盗んだヤツを
許すわけにはいかない！
Yeah, it's unforgivable.
あぁ 許せねえ！
It's the night training for the boy monks.
少年僧たちの 夜の稽古です。
(少年僧たち)はっ はっ…！
It's that jerk, Sora.
ヘッ ソラのヤロウだってばよ！
Begin free sparring!
自由組手 はじめ！
ん？
なに？
What is it?
That's strange.
おかしいってばよ…。
だから 何が？
What is it already?
Oh! I'm getting ticked off!
あぁ～ ムカムカしてきた！
Bow!
(師範)礼！
(少年僧たち)
ありがとうございました！
- Thank you!
You...
テメエ…。
なぁ こんなんでいいのか？
Hey, is it okay like this?
テメエ ふざけてんのか？
Are you screwing around?
ふざけてんのは お前だろ？
You're the one who's screwing around.
稽古だかなんだかしんねえけど➡
I don't know if it's training or what,
but this is like what you're doing.
お前のやってることは
こんなもんだぜ。
この！
ムカムカすんだよ！
You jerk!
You really tick me off.
お前 バカにしてっだろ？
You're messing with me,
aren't you?
何かわかんねえけど
腹が立つんだってばよ！
I don't really know why
but you're making me angry!
ナルト！ あのバカ…。
Naruto...! That idiot!
お前 ナルトって言ったなぁ。
ああ。
Your name's Naruto, right?
Yeah.
もっといい名前をつけてやるよ。
Let me give you an even better one...
グッとくる戒名をよ！
I'll give you a deeply moving
posthumous name.
戒名？
Posthumous name?
Naruto!
ナルト！
やっと
本気になったみてえだなぁ！
It looks like you've
finally gotten serious.
さっき オレとやったときは
今みたいに強かったもんなぁ！
You were strong back
when you fought me...
like you are now!
お前 ムカツク…。
You really tick me off!
Isn't this... a little bit too intense?
ちょっとこれ
激しすぎるんでないかい？
(ソラ)またか…。
Not again...
うぉ～っ!!
《なんだ？ コイツ…。
What's with this guy?
急に 力が空回りしてる》
His power's suddenly
become ineffective.
Those eyes...
They're looking at Sora?
《この目… ソラを？》
《同じ目…》
It's the same eyes.
《なんで お前もあの目を…》
Why are they also looking
at you with those eyes?!
うぅ… うぉ～っ!!
やめなさい ソラ！
That's enough, Sora!
I can't stop!
《やべぇ！ 止まらねえ!!》
戒名 つけそこねたな…。
I failed to give you a posthumous name.
Whoa! What're you doing?!
うわっ！ な… なんだよ!?
いや 汗をふいてあげようと…。
I just thought I'd wipe off the sweat.
Cut it out! That's gross.
やめろよ。 気持わりい。
なぁ サイ…。
ん？
Hey, Sai.
What's a posthumous name?
戒名って なんだ？
Well, I guess it's kind of like...
a nickname.
まぁ… ニックネームみたいなものかな。
It's a name given to the dead.
死者に対してですけど…。
あっ！
So it's like the nicknames
you give people?!
お前がつけてる
あだ名みたいなもんか。
えっ？
That means
it's a sign of friendship, huh?!
友達の証しってことか。
ソラ！
Sora!
Hey!
おい！
ん？
あっ！
What is it?!
どうした？
(忍僧)ナウマ様の墓所が…。
Lord Nauma's grave site!
(ソラ)はぁっ！
Beast Wave Palm!
獣波掌！
獣波烈風掌！
Beast Wave: Palm Hurricane!
They're awesome... your Jutsu!
すっげぇな！ お前の術。
Is this also the wind
Change in Chakra Form?
これも風のチャクラの
形態変化なのか？
何しに来た？
ん？ あぁ。
What're you doing here?
Oh...
I thought I'd give you
a posthumous name too!
オレも お前に
戒名をつけてやろうってな。
Fine... Give me a good one!
いいぜ
いい戒名をつけてくれよ！
Sora! Sora! Sora-cchi.
Soran! Soran-chan.
ソラ ゾラ… ソラッチ！
ソーラン ソランちゃん！
You jerk! Don't mess with me!
テメエ ふざけやがって！
What happened in that temple?
あの寺で 何があったんだよ。
You're... an annoyance!
テメエ… うっとうしいぜ。
Yeah, people have kept thinking
that about me since I was little.
あぁ ガキの頃から
思われ続けてきたってばよ。
You, too... right?
お前もなんだろ？
Then...!
だったら…！
What of it?
どうしたってんだよ。
Yeah! People think I'm a nuisance!
あぁ うっとうしがられてるよ。
But something like that
doesn't bother me at all!
だが そんなことは屁でもねえ。
I'm the one who thinks
I'm a nuisance the most of all!
いちばん
オレをうっとうしく思ってんのは➡
このオレだからな！
That's right...
そうよ。
オレの力がよ うっとうしい。
My power is a nuisance.
You...
お前…。
But nuisance or not,
I can't throw away this power.
でもな うっとうしくても
この力を捨てることはできねえ。
Because I must have revenge...
on the one who killed my father.
オレの父さんを殺したヤツに
復讐するために。
復讐？
Revenge?!
あっ！ 物見鳥だ。
隠し墓か!?
It's a patrol bird! Is it the hidden tombs?!
Naruto!
ナルト！ どこ行ってたのよ。
悪い。
Where were you?
Sorry!
There was contact from
the Shinobi Monks
(ヤマト)ナウマ様の隠し墓へ
向かった忍僧から 連絡があった。
who were heading for
Nauma-sama's hidden tomb.
It seems it was after the tomb
had been broken into
墓が破られ ご遺体は
持ち去られたあとだったそうだ。
and the body taken away.
Say what?!
なんだって!?
クッ…！
At this rate, the other two will also be...
このままでは あとの２つも…。
We're ready. Let's go.
支度はできています
参りましょう。
Right.
I'm going, too!
オレも行きます！
よし。
All right!
All right! I'll pound
those dirty grave robbers!
よっしゃあ
小汚い墓泥棒なんざ➡
オレが ぶっ飛ばしてやる！
I look up at the rainbow I saw as a child.
kodomo no koro mita niji wo
But the prism colors are gone,
ima miageru to nanairo de wa naku
Shrouded in mist instead.
yagate kiri ga kakari
I search for you as you change,
jikan wa sugi kawatte yuku
With the passage of time but you're nowhere to be found.
kimi wo sagashite mo doko ni mo inai
I close my eyes and open my heart.
me wo toji kokoro hiraite
And stare hard again just to see if nothing really changes.
mata nagemete mite mo nani mo kawaranai no ka
I need to know.
tashikamete mitai
I make a wish that the mist will clear.
sunao ni narereba kono kiri ga hareru to
If I'm true to myself and shout it out.
kokoro ni negai sou sakenderu
Maybe by losing something.
nanika wo nakushite shimatta koto de sou
今日の質問は？
「あのソラって奴を
ぶっ倒すために➡
敵の本拠地
火ノ寺について知りたい」。
There must be something I gain as well.
te ni shita mono mo kitto arun darou
って… これアンタじゃない。
だって なんか生意気だし。
ったく…。
But we're still confused about adulthood.
dakedo mada bokura wa otona ni tomadoi
火ノ寺は 木ノ葉随一の忍寺で➡
強固な封印鉄壁は
一度も破られたことがないそうよ。
And searching for the means to live on.
ikito yuku sube sagashiteru
忍僧たちは 仙族の才と呼ばれる
特別な術を操るとか。
Next Episode
地陸さんは 守護人十二士に
選ばれるくらいだから➡
We have received a message
from the Fire Temple.
It seems all of the hidden tombs
have been violated by the enemy.
その強さは 折り紙つきね。
ふ～ん。 そういえばさ
火ノ寺って➡
They got us.
So what's the present situation?
Team Kakashi is on the way.
結構 頭 剃ってないヤツいるよな
なんで？
What's the enemy after?
So they were after the bodies
of the Shinobi
さぁ？ 例えば 見習いだとか。
chosen to become
Guardian Shinobi Twelve, huh?
あっ そっか！ ヤツは見習いか。
We know nothing about any developments
regarding the Akatsuki and Orochimaru,
いや 例えばだから。
うん 見習いじゃ しようがねえな。
so we're unable to fathom
Danzo-sama's true intentions...
しばらくは
なまあたたか～く見守ってやる。
There are causes for
concern everywhere.
Then we should start by dealing
with what's within reach.
まぁ 質問者も
納得したみたいだし➡
A New Enemy
Next time: "A New Enemy"
これにて終了ってことで。
"THE LEAF ASK-US-ANYTHING INVESTIGATION TEAM"
— The Leaf Ask-Us-Anything Investigation Team!
And now for today's question...
I want to know about the enemy
home base, the Fire Temple,
so I can pound that Sora jerk...
— Hey, isn't this you?
— But he's such a smart-aleck.
Good grief.
The Fire Temple is the greatest
shinobi temple in the Leaf.
I hear the powerful “Iron Wall Seal”
has never been broken through.
It seems the shinobi monks wield
a special jutsu called
the “Gift of the Sages”.
And Chiriku-san was chosen as one
of the Guardian Shinobi Twelve.
So their power is the genuine article.
Speaking of which, it looks like
there are quite a few guys
without shaved heads in
the Fire Temple. Why is that?
Who knows?
For example, maybe they're novice monks
or something...
I get it. He's a novice!
No, it's just an example...
Well, I guess it can't be helped
if he's a novice.
I'll watch over him warmly.
Well, it appears the questioner
is satisfied,
so that brings us to the conclusion...
"QUESTION FOUR: THE SECRET OF THE FIRE TEMPLE"
"SOLVED!"